Vancouver, BC(778) 862-7477

Eiliya Abedianamiri



Highlights

- Well-familiar with TypeScript and JavaScript, Next.js, Nest.js, React (Native), MVC design pattern, OOP, Databases (SQL, MongoDB, Neo4j), Git workflows, Agile, Scrum, Kanban, and Continuous Integration/Development.
- Detail-oriented personality; Avid fast learner and an early-adapter.
- Web Developer with 5+ years of experience designing and building complex web application, configuring system environments, and enhancing the existing web apps while specializing on the back-end.
- Will graduate from BCIT at May 2023, approximately.
- Self-taught advanced PHP, Object Oriented Programming, and C#. Also familiar with Python, C++, Java.

Technical Skills

Programming Languages	TypeScript, JavaScript, PHP, C#, (less familiar with: Python, Java, C++, R, Ruby).
Web Frameworks	Next.js, Nest.js, ASP.NET, Laravel, Socket.io, Electron, React Native (Expo), SignalR.
Front-end	Low/High-fidelity Prototyping , Figma , HTML, CSS3, React (Native) , Tailwind, Bootstrap
Tools/Techniques	5, WPF, Storybook, styled components, Atomic Folder Structure (React.js-related).
Basic Knowledge of Web	Web Protocols (AJAX, HTTP(S), WebSocket (WS), Long Polling, Web Server, W3C), Web
Concepts	APIs (REST, Soup).
Database	MySQL, MS SQL, SQLite, MongoDB, Neo4j, Redis.
DevOps Tools	VMware, VirtualBox, Docker, Azure, AWS, GitHub Actions, Vercel, Railway, Nginx,
	Apache.
Operation Systems	Windows Server, Linux (CentOS, Ubuntu, Kali, Manjaro).
Productivity &	Agile, Scrum, Kanban, Jira, Git, Trello, Microsoft Office Products, Google Docs, Google
Workflows	Slides, Miro, FigJam, Draw.io, Excalidraw.
Networking	VDS, VPS, Hosting, VPN (L2TP, PPTP, OpenVPN, Outline VPN, V2ray), Port Forwarding,
Concepts/Techniques	DNS configuration, Network+, Client-server model, Proxying.
<u>Currently Learning</u>	Next.js (new 13th version),

Projects

COUGHIE [Private 1]

2022 December

• Designing and ideating in a team of 4 other members while aiming to build a mobile-first web platform that helps vape smokers quit their vaping habit by tracking their successions and growing digital plants as a reward system.

I GOT A QUEERY (IGAQ) [Open-source 2]

2022 September – November

- Worked in a team of 3 Full-Stackers and 4 other Designers & Developers on a back-end REST API server and a
 front-end Next.js web application. <u>IGAQ</u> provides a safe space for the members of the LGBTQ+ community to
 ask questions, share stories, and read resources about all things LGBTQ+.
- Helped teammates grow and learn new technologies fast by coaching and guiding them towards grasping the
 required skills and instantly applying them to our project, resulted a positive team-flow and balanced
 contributions among the team.

- Designed a graph database in <u>Neo4j</u>, coded services and repositories and wrote tests using the <u>Nest.js</u>, and <u>Passport.js</u> for our authentication library.
- Contributed to the front-end Next.js application by helping teammates connect the front-end code to backend and find way arounds for any blockers that they encounter. Actively communicating and having standups to effectively catch up to the next MVP.

POKER GAME [Private ♠]

2021 - current

Database:

- Designed a large scaled SQL database using Microsoft SQL Server Management with MSSQL DBMS, resulted to a normalized and scalable relational database.
- Organized and managed the project's database access layer using Entity Framework Core, an Objectrelational Model (ORM), which reduced the redundant queries and simplified caching and separating the database layer in the software.

Back-End API:

- Building the core endpoint of the platform using .NET Core Web API libraries, Entity Framework Core, and custom Authentication and Authorization.
- Designed a REST API using Swagger tools such as Swagger editor and Swagger UI which resulted to a communicative and technical API documentation along with different examples.

Game API (Back-End):

- Built the game engine part of the platform (provider) using ASP.NET Core, SignalR, and external Poker Hand Evaluation library from https://github.com/platatat/SnapCall. This endpoint communicates with any frontend application via a REST API and JWT authentication; Talks to the Core Back-End which holds the key features to run the app and updates the main database.
- Working with one other teammate and actively communicating in order to split the work and develop the solutions in an agile fast-paced way.

Front-Ends:

- Building a mobile frontend native application using React Native, Expo tools and connecting it to the Back End API via REST API and Web Sockets (SignalR). The first MVP is still in progress.
- Contributed to building a Desktop version of the application in WPF by testing and giving feedback to my teammate. The first MVP is done so far.

ONLINE 2D GAME [Open-source 2]

2022 May

- Built a 2D online multiplayer in-browser game, integrating Web Socket via the Socket.io library in Node.js, to speed up a live turn-based game. Used game assets built by the design students.
- Developed a standalone frontend for the game using vanilla JavaScript and Webpack, resulted to an offline fully-functional 2D game compatible with all web browsers.
- Built an API server using Express.js, following the MVC design pattern, which resulted to an organized and scalable server that is ready to handle API request coming from client applications.

MY HOME SERVER [Personal]

2022 March

 Setup and configured a home server. Installed and configured Windows Server 2019, MySQL, MS SQL, MongoDB, Neo4j, Docker Desktop, VPN (L2TP, and PPTP on windows), OpenVPN (using a public Docker Image). For personal usages. • Developed a web bot using Selenium and Node.js that by-passes the two-step verification by reading the inbox of an email account via IMAP protocol, resulted a bot that **automatically** looks for the closest appointment on a platform and books it **instantly**.

DYNAMIC PAYMENT TUNNEL [Private 1]

2019 - 2020

- Built a dynamic API and Payment interface that mirrors any other payment services and acts as a third-party payment terminal, serving as a payment method for any website.
- Optimized the speed of a web application by caching the user's database connection in their back-end stored Cookie Session, decreased MySQL's network load and attracted users by 50%.
- Revised the database design, redesigning the ERDs of SQL tables and rewriting the Models, enhanced the speed of MySQL queries and saved more memory usage.

WITCHER PHP FRAMEWORK [Open-source 2]

2017 - 2021

• Developed a full MVC framework using only PHP and Object-oriented programming, making my other projects faster, reliable, and more secure.

LOTTERY GAME WEBSITE [Open-source 2]

2017

- Developed a full website using PHP, HTML, CSS, and JavaScript, along with a thorough admin panel **from** scratch.
- Built a live game engine, using raw PHP and cron job, to automate games and find the winners.

Education

BRITISH COLUMBIA INSTITUTE OF TECHNOLOGY

2021 - 2023

Diploma - Full-Stack Web Development

• GPA: 92

Experience

PEER TUTOR | CONTRACT

2022 - current

British Columbia Institute of Technology – Vancouver, BC

 Actively communicating with students and helping them better understand the course materials related to Computer Science.

FULL-STACK WEB DEVELOPER | CONTRACT

2021 – 2022 February

Basaz Construction Ltd. – Vancouver, BC

 Built a full-stack website using Laravel, HTML, CSS, and JavaScript, resulted a landing page website with a contact form

SOFTWARE ENGINEER | INTERNSHIP

2018 - 2019

Radin Hamkaran Behta Co. – Tehran, Iran

- Configured a L2tp/IPsec VPN by forwarding ports from a virtual Windows Server to the public internet, isolating the internal network of a company's computers.
- Learned basics of C# and .NET framework.

Khakbaz Md. Medical Clinic – Tehran, Iran

• Launched a website with admin panel, using PHP, HTML, CSS, JavaScript, and MySQL to establish a doctor's recognition over the internet and allow them managing their website's content. (Open-source)